# Mark McDonald

Cambridge, Massachusetts mark.mcdonald1@icloud.com

(561) 213-2871 (mobile)

After a career in corporate financial and technology management, I am pursuing a degree in Software Engineering with a focus in Data Science. I aim to combine my business and technical skills to deliver A.I. solutions to small and medium-sized businesses. I believe that Deep Learning can be applied to nearly all aspects of business and will become a critical success factor in the near future. My goal is to help businesses exploit these technologies to improve their customers' experience as well as their employee satisfaction and performance.

## **EDUCATION**

#### **Harvard Extension School**

Masters in Software Engineering – Degree Candidate (June 2020)

**Certificate**: Data Science **Languages**: Python, Java, C

Platforms & Technologies: Keras, Pandas, OpenCV, Git, Docker, Spring, Flask, Django,

AWS, Microservices, Deep Learning, ROS, Maven, Unix, ROS,

Raspberry Pi

## **Georgia State University**

Master of Science, Computer Information Systems // Focus: E-Commerce / Project Management

#### **Iowa State University**

Bachelor of Business Administration, Accounting // Minor: German

#### Schiller International University - Heidelberg, Germany

Semester Abroad - International Business

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Director - Finance**

Primetals Technologies USA (formerly Siemens Metals Technologies), Worcester, Massachusetts Metallurgical Spares & Service (November 2013 – April 2017)

Global leader in the metals machinery supply market that engineers, manufactures, installs and services customers across the Globe. Operates in 50 countries with 12,000 employees. Led Financial function of the international service business segment covering multiple locations supporting Sales, Engineering and Manufacturing functions.

#### **Director - Process Management**

Siemens Industry, Inc. – Metals Business Unit (May 2010 - October 2013), Worcester, Massachusetts Process alignment across USA locations. Focus on alignment of business and financial processes, as well as, supporting SAP configurations. Led integration of new acquisitions.

## **Director - Global Projects / Mergers & Acquisitions**

Siemens Industry, Inc. (August 2005 - May 2010)

Canonsburg, Pennsylvania / Worcester, Massachusetts

Led integration of several newly acquired companies into the Siemens global landscape. In addition to Due Diligence efforts, my work focused on the integration of Finance, Accounting, HR, IT, Banking, ERP(SAP) Applications, Travel Management and shared services.

## **Chief Information Officer**

Siemens Information & Communication Mobile (August 2003 – July 2005), Boca Raton, FL Responsible for SAP and IT systems for company of 500 users in 13 locations.

## **Director of Regional Management**

Siemens Information & Communication Mobile (April 2002 – July 2003), Munich, Germany Managed the IT strategy for international locations (USA, China, Italy, Germany, Taiwan)

## **Corporate Performance Controller**

Siemens Corporate Headquarters

Performance Controlling (November 1999 – Mar 2002), Munich, Germany Global financial consolidation and performance analysis for shareholders and the Siemens executive Board of Directors.

# Finance Project Leader / SAP (FI/CO)

Siemens Electronics Assembly Equipment (March 1998 - October 1999), Norcross, GA

## **Senior Financial Analyst**

Siemens Energy & Automation

Corporate Financial Planning & Analysis (January 1994 - March 1998), Alpharetta, GA

## **Accounting Consultant**

Management & Planning Services (December 1992 - January 1994), Atlanta, GA

# **TRAINING & SPECIAL SKILLS**

- Graduate of the IMD Global Executive Program
- Siemens Management Qualification Training
- SAP Training: Controlling, ABAP Programming, A/R & A/P, Report Writer, SEM Overview, BW Analysis, BW Configuration, BW Web Reporting
- Fluent in English (native) and German